PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Statistics graduate knowledgeable in data processing, analysis, surveys and market research. Experienced in providing reports on small to large data sets and working with teams to increase productivity or efficiency. Delivers exceptional customer service and is open to expanding knowledge base.

Core Competencies

Data Analytics | SAS | R | STATA | SQL | MS Excel | Multivariate Regression | Decision Trees | VBA | Pivot Table | Monte Carlo Simulation | Market Research | Customer Service

EDUCATION

- MS in Education, Statistics, Measurement, Assessment and Research Technology | University of Pennsylvania | 2020
- BA, Economics | Ohio State University | 2017

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

03/2019 – 07/2019 | Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences | Beijing, China | Research Associate

- Researched 10+ global megacities traffic conditions and compared them to China's megacities to identify congestion solutions.
- Identified one of the root causes of congestion as lacking regulation on the number of plates sold per year.

 Applied Game Theory to automation lotteries and visualized data in excel using pivot tables.
- Responsible for analyzing historical data in the rate of return across different assets and presenting to internal clients. Concluded that investing in the housing market can yield the highest return in the long term.
- Spearheaded a project to check statistical anomalies and generate multivariate regression analysis in R.

01/2018 - 11/2018 | Amazon.com Inc. | Beijing, China | Investigation Analyst

- Member of the Global Selling Team verifying business and personal backgrounds to qualify sellers to sell in North America, Japan, and Australia marketplaces.
- Aided in initiating the Automation process of collecting seller credentials to build a database that used a learning algorithm to increase efficiency by 50% within two quarters.
- Identified workflow improvements and aided managers and the operation function in implementing new strategies to enhance workforce efficiency.

06/2016 - 08/2016 | China Construction Bank Corp | Beijing, China | Sales Analyst Intern

- Part of the Private Wealth Management team aiding sales managers with building a program to serve Chinese nationals in diversifying their investment assets.
- Arranged daily morning meetings and provided market research to the team for review and discussion.
- Developed and documented a process framework for future interns to perform and present market research.

ORGANIZATIONS & EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- English Conversation Program | Ohio State University | Project Facilitator
 - ♦ Facilitated international students with increasing their English skills and understanding of American cultures.
 - ◆ Led discussions with international and American students to increase the college satisfaction rate to 100%.
- Toastmasters
- The Penn Club
- Penn Actuarial Society

RELEVANT COURSEWORK

Data Processing & Analysis, Statistical Methods: Regression & Analysis of Variance, Linear Regression, Calculus II, Statistics for Business, Policy Research, Survey Methods and Design, The Healthcare Services System, Microeconomics, Game Theory Economics, Econometrics, Cost & Management Accounting, Management Information System, Machine Learning